chat-avenue.com 2019-10-01

# #1 Chat Avenue - Privacy Statement

**#1 Chat Avenue** has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses the information gathering and dissemination practices for this Web site: [ www.chat-avenue.com](https://www.chat-avenue.com/)

### Important Note to Children under 13:

Children under 13 are NOT allowed to use any of our chat rooms or allowed to participate in any way, shape, or form on this website. 

#1 Chat Avenue is a general audience community chat site that allows users to interact with other users via chat rooms, [message forums](https://forum.chat-avenue.com/) and our [blog](https://www.chat-avenue.com/blog/). It has seventeen different chat "categories" or "topics" to choose from and a message forum with various topics. The chat rooms are all accessible via mobile APPs for Android and IOS. All users **MUST** be 13 or over to participate. 

### _Personal Information_

At #1 Chat Avenue, we are committed to protecting all your personal data and your privacy. 

Similar to when you visit and interact with other websites and services available via the Internet, when you visit our website we gather certain information and store it within log files. This information may include but is not limited to Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, system configuration information, URLs of referring pages, and locale and language preferences. 

In general, this website does not request any personal information or collect any information that personally identifies you or allows you to be personally contacted, in order to participate. You are always welcome to participate in our chat rooms as a guest user. However, certain areas of the site such as our forums or registering a personal username for the chat rooms does collect certain information that you voluntarily provide us such as an email address. Furthermore, our access logs or stored information may reveal your Internet Service Provider, your IP address and the e-mail addresses of those who communicate with us via e-mail and signs up for our message forums or chat rooms. All communication from emails to us by users known or identified as being under the age of 13 are deleted immediately.

The web site server logs WILL store the IP address of individual accessing this web site. The IP address, through your ISP, can identify the household where the user accessed this website. This specific information is not accessible by our website or our staff, but we may report unlawful activity to your ISP in order to identify you for possible legal action. 

The IP address or any other personal data collected will never be shared or revealed unless under the following circumstances: 

1) If a government agency, or an attorney, subpoenas your private information, or makes a formal and official request for discovery pursuant to any legal action, or pending legal action against YOU. For criminal matters, you must be a member of a law enforcement agency or community.

2) If our attorney requests this information relevant to a pending or current legal matter in which you are a potential or actual party or otherwise contributed in some way to the causation of the legal matter at hand. 

Please note that IP address logs are only stored for a limited period of time and may or may not be available at the time of request. Any formal requests should be done sooner rather than later. 

We do not share any personal information with any third parties nor do we use any personal information for any purposes.

This website will never sell, share, rent, or disclose your personal information to anyone except as necessary to provide our services or as otherwise described in this privacy policy.

This site utilizes chat rooms, web cams, audio, mobile apps, and forums which can potentially result in the disclosure of personal information publicly. If we become aware of this (regardless of the users age), we will delete any personal information including, but not limited to, email addresses, phone numbers, names, and home addresses immediately. Please note that we DO NOT store logs of chat conversations greater than one full day. It is the responsibility of the user to not disclose any personal information to those they come in contact with via our chat rooms.

When you register for a user account on any of our chat rooms or forums, we collect your email address. This information is required to identify you as an end user and permit you to access your account. By voluntarily providing us with such information, you represent that you are the owner of such personal data or otherwise have the requisite consent to provide it to us.

We reserve the right to provide information to all law enforcement agencies when images depicting nudity of users under the age of 18 are found to be uploaded either through an image transfer or an avatar. The information provided can include, but not limited to, an IP address, MAC address, or email address.

### _How do we protect personal information?_

Our website is scanned on a regular basis for virus', security holes, malware and known vulnerabilities. All information is stored behind secured networks and is only accessible by a very limited number of persons having special access rights to such items. They are required to keep information confidential. All information supplied is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.

### _Do we use cookies?_

In some areas of the website, we do. Cookies are small files that a website or service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser, if you allow it to. This enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain specific information. For example, we use cookies to remember your username and settings in some of our chat rooms. Through your browser settings, you can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off cookies altogether.

### _GDPR Specific Guidelines_

If you are a resident of Europe, you have the right to access personal information we hold about you and to ask that your personal information be corrected, updated, or deleted. If you would like to exercise this right, please contact us through the [contact us](https://www.chat-avenue.com/contact.html) page. If you are a European resident, any personal information or data stored would be in order to fulfill your participation in our chat rooms, forums and other areas of the website. Please note that your information will be transferred outside of Europe, including, but not limited to, datacenter's in Canada and the United States of America. When you provide us with personal information through the website, we will maintain this information in our records for a limited time frame or until you ask us to delete this information and are a EU resident. 

In certain circumstances, personal data information including IP addresses can be provided to law enforcement agencies. If you are a member of law enforcement including from those protected GDPR countries, and require data, please visit the [law enforcement](https://www.chat-avenue.com/lawenforcement.html) page. Data collection is lawful, according to GDPR, if the processing of data is carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the controller. Law enforcement is the perfect example of such. Therefore, courts and police can ask for data and retain them. 

### _For Parents: Children's Privacy_

Our website is not directed at, or intended for use by, children under the age of 13. This website is a general audience website but we have blocked out users under 13 on the kids chat area of our site that may be misunderstood by some as being directed for users under 13. We do not knowingly allow anyone to provide any personal identifying information on our website. Everyone must take caution before sending personal information over the Internet and through chatrooms. If you have discovered that your child (who is under 13) has registered for a message forum account, please [contact us](https://www.chat-avenue.com/contact.html) with your child's message forum username and we will have that account and any message postings he/she has made, removed immediately.

### Important Note:

The [kids chat](https://www.chat-avenue.com/kidchat.html) is for older kids. Specifically, users aged 13-16 years old. Our moderators will, on occasion, implement an age verification process to prevent users, under the age of 13 or over the age of 16, to participate in the Kids chat. We sometimes do allow users over 16, but under 19, to participate, but prefer them to utilize our [teen chat room](https://www.chat-avenue.com/teenchat.html) instead. 

The [Adult Chat](https://www.chat-avenue.com/adultchat.html) and [sex chat](https://www.chat-avenue.com/sexchat.html) rooms are strictly for users 18 and over. Due to the content of the rooms, they are constantly monitored to ensure users underage will be removed. However, you, as a user, will be held solely responsible for your actions if you participate in those chat rooms. Age cannot be easily verifiable. 

### _Public Forums_

This website makes chat rooms and message forums available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information to others. As mentioned earlier email addresses are required in order to register for certain areas of the website and IP addresses are stored in our access logs, but those are never shared with any third parties and are only used for registration purposes. In addition, users must be 13 years or older in order to register to the forums. As mentioned previously, if your child is under 13 and has registered for a forums account, please contact us immediately with their username and we will have it removed immediately.

#1 Chat Avenue will never require a user to submit any more personal information other than what is required for activity participation. (Age verification and/or chat nickname) 

### _Advertisers_

We use an outside ad company to display ads on our site. These ads may contain cookies. Cookies received with banner ads are collected by our ad company, and we do not have access to this information. This information is used for tracking purposes only and are not and cannot be used to obtain personal information about you or anyone else. 

### _Contact Us_

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can write us an email using our the contact form:   

Please also make sure you have reviewed and read our [Terms of Service](https://www.chat-avenue.com/tos.html) page.
